You sure you've got Wrath and not Gluttony?
We just bought all those supplies...
How much do you need to eat?
Rage burns a lot of calories.
With all the eating you do, I have
to wonder where it all goes.
Hang on! Don't do it!
If you could please handle the repairs.
The Twilight Swordsman
Sure thing. That'll be
costing you extra, though.
Huh? Where's Myne?
Just does whatever she wants... Myne!
This place seems pretty peaceful.
We're near Galia at this point.
That means monsters pose a big threat.
I'd bet there's someone
very powerful protecting this village.
Makes sense. What's that castle?
Based on where we are,
I'd say that's Hausen.
I thought that Seifort had
the only castle around here.
Excuse me, where's the mayor?
We're looking to stay
in this village for a while.
I'm this village's chief.
That's a holy sword.
You're a holy knight?
I get it. He must be defending the village.
You'd like to stay, is that right?
First, I'd like you to cross swords
with me for a bit.
Identify, eh?
You're level 1, but with stats
over two million.
When did you use Identify on me?!
Are we doing this or not?
Hey! Don't drop me!
I take it this means we don't get to stay...
Far from it. I sense a purpose
in this chance meeting.
You're welcome to stay.
Really?
On one condition, though.
What's that?
During your stay, you'll train under me.
Why train me?
Let's just call it the whims of an old man.
This is fishy.
Yeah...
You don't know how to counter Identify.
You're not making the most of
your other skills, either.
I feel like your body isn't
accustomed to its strength.
The way you fight will serve
you well against monsters
but less so against other humans.
There's nothing for you to lose
from my instruction.
What do you say?
And he's not asking for anything in return?
Just keeps getting sketchier.
But... it's not every day you get an offer
to learn directly from a holy knight.
Suit yourself, then.
I'm Fate Graphite. Nice to meet you.
Aaron Barbatos.
Myne?
Is this your companion?
Yes.
Well... a warrior. And a very
capable one at that.
You can tell?
Fate, we can camp out over there.
I already found us a place to stay, Myne.
We're starting with hand-to-hand?
Correct. It's the best way
to learn to control your stats.
That's something you
have trouble with, right?
I guess you can see right through me.
It happens all the time with warriors
who suddenly become much stronger.
Come, Fate, give it a try.
Arms closer to your body.
Lower your hips.
Hands like this.
Ow!
You're tensing up too much.
You need to loosen up, like this!
So fast!
The more you flex, the weaker
and slower your movement.
You'll generate more power
from a relaxed state.
And beyond that, you'll be able to
pursue unconscious power!
Right!
Hungry...
He's right, I can move better
if I don't tense up.
And if I can control my stats better...
Damn it! Why is Gluttony acting up now?!
Your eye color has changed. What's wrong?
This is bad...
Well, you're suddenly moving much better.
You're a good teacher, Aaron.
I see... How about this, then?!
You're able to move pretty well
despite being nearly starved now.
Tomorrow, we'll move on to
actual combat practice.
Right!
I can smell a monster...
Is there a monster in that castle?
What in the world?
Aaron!
What is wrong with her...?
I'm sorry about this.
Don't worry about it. I'll go ask
the villagers to share some food.
Dammit, as if being nearly starved
wasn't bad enough...
This is your fault, y'know? Yours.
Whoa, I wouldn't do that if I were you.
Getting reckless all of a sudden, huh?
Is that... Aaron?
So this would be his son?
He looks like you, Fate.
I get it now.
Looks like there's a reason he's the head
of a village in the middle of nowhere.
I want you to parry my strike with that stick.
With just a wooden stick?!
It's obviously gonna break!
You've been training under me.
You'll manage.
Understood. Whenever you're ready!
Now then, let's begin!
Predict the angle and path of the sword...
Then with the minimum amount of strength,
like you're sliding across the blade!
Well done!
You're able to control those stats, now.
Yes! Thank you so much.
Here's a reward from me.
From you, Myne?
Good. It suits you.
I tried to warn you.
You're leaving early tomorrow?
Yeah. Thank you for everything you've done.
You should thank him, too, Myne.
Myne...
Sorry about her.
It's no problem. By all means, eat your fill.
There's plenty of meat and vegetables, still.
It all tastes the same.
My sense of taste is gone.
That's the price she pays for Wrath.
I've got a mission.
A mission...?
A goal you need done, eh?
Is there something in that castle?
Hausen...
It used to be my castle.
That was 15 years ago.
I had left Hausen on royal orders...
I'm going to defend the castle
while Father is away!
My family and my people
fell to a crowned beast
that had grown from accumulated aggression...
Ever since, Hausen has belonged to
the Genesis of Death, a lich lord.
My family is still in its clutches.
What's the matter, Fate?
I need to step out for a sec...
You're headed to the castle?
Aaron...
I'll join you.
This is a good chance
to put my past to rest.
I'll watch the village.
How's 50 gold coins sound?
Magic arrows?
With a petrifying effect
caused by Sandstorm.
That's a technique so difficult to manage,
they've stopped studying it in the capital.
I'm impressed.
It's nothing.
The credit all belongs to me.
Let's keep moving!
Right.
From the second floor?
An invitation, most likely. Let's go.
Impossible!
Father!
It can't be...
Welcome home, dear.
Welcome home, master.
We've been waiting so long for you, dear.
Luke... Diana...
You're both...
You were both still alive.
What do you mean, Father?
You must be exhausted, dear.
Did you carry out your mission
from the king, Father?
I did. The stampede has been dealt with.
That's amazing!
Could you tell us more about it?
I suppose I can...
What's going on here, Greed?
They might look alive,
but they're definitely not.
This is an illusion spell.
All of this is an illusion?
Oh, you two, that's enough chat for now.
You should get some rest, dear.
Oh, Father, did you bring me a souvenir?
Of course I did.
All right!
Aaron!
You've grown so strong, Luke!
Because I had to protect the castle
in your absence, Father.
For so many long, long, unending years...!
While you only care about work, work, work!
You abandoned us to monsters
for your duty in the capital!
How could you show up
after all this time to kill us?!
We're still alive!
Aaron, I can get rid of the illusions.
Greed, I need the black scythe.
It can cut through the effects
caused by a skill, true.
But when it does that,
it'll mean slaying them.
Souls that are devoured
by Gluttony can never pass on.
It's like being confined to an endless hell
with no hope of salvation!
I can't do that to them...
Fate!
Sorry, but would you
let me handle my family?
In that case, I'll find the lich lord!
Luke... you truly have become strong.
You must have followed my teachings,
never shirking your training.
This place is thick with its scent.
There!
No more hide and seek!
There's the lich lord!
All of its stats are above a million!
Genesis of Death
[Stats]
Vitality:
Strength:
Magic:
Spirit:
Agility:
[Skills]
Illusion magic
Magic Boost (Large)
Spirit Boost (large)
Don't tense up, and use the minimal
amount of strength necessary...!
Its power to control corpses is still intact.
Save us, please...
Help... please...
I can't attack them.
Fate, behind you!
Sorry about the delay. I'm ready now.
I've cut the tendons in their limbs
to immobilize them.
Now, then...
Diana.
Reconsider...
Reconsider, dear.
She's right, Father. Why is it always
you on these dangerous missions?
It's all right. You don't need to worry.
Once I've dealt with the monsters,
I'll be right back.
That's right. If I had...
If I had returned faster...
But now, I can end your suffering.
Grand Cross!
I've nearly got him...!
What do we do?
His son's sword...?
Greed?
Just don't make a habit out of it.
Right!
Aaron! I'll help!
That's...
Let's end this!
I think we will.
Grand Cross!
I'm sorry I kept you waiting for so long.
It's not your fault, Father.
Luke... I...
Besides, you saved us in the end.
Diana.
If only I had made up my mind sooner...
No. I should've never left your side.
I knew that you both were more
important than any orders, and yet...
It must've been painful.
Forgive me.
We're okay now.
And for our sake, please,
do what you think is right.
Right. I promise.
I will live in a way
that honors your memory.
I know it's late, Luke,
but I have your souvenir.
Thank you, Father.
Diana. Luke.
Gluttony skill has activated.
No one is interrupting this.
It's important... that he gets
to say goodbye...
Go on ahead. Wait for me.
When I've finished what
I must do... I'll join you.
You exceeded your level limit?!
Yes. Likely because of fighting
at your side, Fate.
Sounds possible.
It'd need to be someone that you,
with your skill, accept, though...
Seriously?
Now then, I have a horde of monsters
that need dealing with.
Skeletons!
There's still this many left?
Care for a race, then?
Interesting. Let's do it!
Right!
Late.
Calm down, Myne!
And put Sloth down!
Your fee, and a little extra as an apology.
What a mercenary...
Need money to rebuild village.
For the village, huh?
Money doesn't lie. You learn that
if you live long enough.
Long enough...?
I'd been thinking I'd seen you somewhere
before... and now I remember.
Fifty years ago, monsters appeared in
this town, and I caught a glimpse of you.
Fifty years ago?!
Yes, and you looked exactly the same...
Even then, you were the picture of a warrior.
You've got a good eye.
With a millennium of training,
Aaron, you might catch up to me.
A millennium?!
A harsh appraisal!
It's true, though. Humans have their limits.
What does that make you, then?
I'm a phantom who's not allowed to die.
A phantom...?
And it's time you paid me back.
Myne...
Your eyes are back to normal.
I have a condition where I need
to slay monsters regularly.
If I don't, my eyes turn red—
And a great burden
is inflicted on your soul, eh?
Fate, when you've done what you
need to do, come back here.
I have something important to tell you.
The philosopher's stone, capable
of healing any illness or wound!
I didn't think you'd really find it!
Maybe immortality isn't out of
reach after all, Rafale!
Indeed.
Begging your pardon, sir.
Did anything of note happen
while we were gone?
I haven't seen Hado around.
I need to inform you...
Hado's dead?
Yes. According to those who were there,
Corpse is not a monster, but a warrior.
That Corpse...
Just who is he?
The Village of Lost Memories
"The Village of Lost Memories."